<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[tags:elisp | Umar Ahmad]]></title>
  <link href="http://gleek.github.io/blog/tags/elisp/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://gleek.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2017-04-08T01:35:17+05:30</updated>
  <id>http://gleek.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Umar Ahmad]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Customizing Emacs]]></title>
    <link href="http://gleek.github.io/blog/2014/04/10/customizing-emacs/"/>
    <updated>2014-04-10T18:32:50+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://gleek.github.io/blog/2014/04/10/customizing-emacs</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/ARlXYE_wnAvftBBl2UEvu-z9SpH-q3lyYNukRnNRwbUnXt6fGTP304OloJ3sJ3pSlMr_9QnPr_RxKamv65BFkEUqUEKB0TftIzNuOaiabipF1DNMYLzYReB_40Qr2TbbDndKYzeY5-MPUNmyzH9xmsuhWxmpywT4U5ayHJo2-dGy1W7wRlY2kY7QtTvneNt4OqGGZlqsSZLYM3WVcVwWFxBeJzPxirItCLPzRoRNPfdZZRy6k31JS65TU3WYW-7hvOcTuoZ6vDJSj2K3HyD73dpJ7YjNUwmJB9tjNzy7bqUXm5ftnuG14qPKs1Gtz1jpAGESfgafhUeLQL1pvDWP-VBQDLIwYaXr-XFTatPTgalAAPNd66J-cJ_J0O1OkF1DM-KM4RjqDhLkMOT9-RM5fkrG5_Rnibw32yJho_cGYTyk7523_CnePswMWjMtmMrTI4zyrsaRYVqBjfRxwznHExq1nAwuR-NSmP2EeeLvPYFP6ZSyMWyZCga2K0LH6J9-Qa8aHdkneuQ9ti6w0QGEJHr9HinsGuWBuALKd2H0ZlPxrwhOdKSyEIaWgq2mkt0vL653PCK4sN5zGZZte3kc7LL3I4WZhlN1oaRsXbIRTJaLEYhQTYj4BrRDS-59IHAwl2Ddf_AzsF9r7c6cKs-A2DQL2QpM2Nb5gU5Ae05pIw=w270-h217-no" style="display:block;margin:auto; "><br>
I believe the environment in which one works is directly responsible for one&rsquo;s productivity. It&rsquo;s the reason I think, it&rsquo;s important to choose the right editor, font, etc.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>I used notepad, notepad++ in my Windows days. I have to say I spent a lot of time with notepad++ and it was my favorite at that time. My notepad++ days ended when one of my friends recommended <a title="Sublime Text" href="http://www.sublimetext.com/" target="_blank">Sublime Text</a> to me. It was the best editor I ever had encountered till that time. The most important thing was that &lsquo;it was cross-platform&rsquo;.</p>

<h3>Switching to Emacs</h3>

<p>I switched to Emacs mainly because of it&rsquo;s philosophy, as I am willing to put up with a much steeper learning curve if it makes me more productive or more comfortable in general. Now that some time has passed I&rsquo;m much faster with Emacs than on any other text editor I use (namely Sublime Text, gedit and Vim). The other reason is it&rsquo;s features. Emacs has tonnes of features which are very hard to replicate in other text editors. These may include from Shell mode to IRC-Chat to E-mail to even playing games inside Emacs.</p>

<h3>Things to do after installation</h3>

<ul>
<li><strong><a href="http://www.emacswiki.org/emacs/CuaMode">Enable CUA Mode</a></strong>:  This basically enables <kbd>Ctrl</kbd>+<kbd>X</kbd>, <kbd>Ctrl</kbd>+<kbd>C</kbd>, <kbd>Ctrl</kbd>+<kbd>V</kbd>, <kbd>Ctrl</kbd>+<kbd>Z</kbd>, <kbd>Shift</kbd>+<kbd>Arrow</kbd> keys. Different key-bindings for such commands are sometimes annoying. Easiest way to do it is Options > Use CUA Keys.</li>
<li><strong>Hide the Toolbar</strong>: The Toolbar is pretty much useless if you are well versed with the key-bindings. Also it frees up a lot of writing space. You can even disable the Menu Bar (can be accessed by <kbd>F10</kbd>  from inside Emacs).</li>
<li><strong><a href="http://melpa.milkbox.net">Adding Melpa package Archive</a></strong>: This gives you tonnes of packages you won&rsquo;t find on default archives. There are other managers out there like <a href="http://marmalade-repo.org/" target="_blank">Marmalade</a> which you can add too, but I feel that it&rsquo;s not that frequently updated. But nonetheless you can add both of them.</li>
<li><strong>Choosing the right theme</strong>: I recommend using a theme which is a bit easy on the eyes such as <a href="http://melpa.milkbox.net/packages/monokai-theme-20140310.1330.el">Monokai</a>, <a href="http://melpa.milkbox.net/packages/zenburn-theme-20140402.547.el" title="">Zenburn</a> or <a href="http://melpa.milkbox.net/packages/solarized-theme-20140409.338.tar">Solarized</a> themes. I recommend you install them from the package manager.</li>
<li><strong>Choosing the right font</strong>: This is more of a personal choice actually. Any monospace font would do the job. You can refer to <a href="http://hivelogic.com/articles/top-10-programming-fonts">Dan&rsquo;s article</a> or <a href="http://blog.codinghorror.com/revisiting-programming-fonts">Jeff&rsquo;s Blog</a> for more details.</li>
<li><strong>Making your scroll smooth</strong>: Emacs Scroll will seem a bit weird to some people who are new to it. To remove the jumpy effect of scroll you can add following lines in your .emacs file</li>
</ul>


<p><code>scheme
(setq redisplay-dont-pause t
  scroll-margin 1
  scroll-step 1
  scroll-conservatively 10000
  scroll-preserve-screen-position 1)
</code></p>

<p>Well these are some basic customization which should be done by everyone using Emacs. You can add more features to Emacs by simply searching the package archive.</p>

<p>If you&rsquo;re a confused with the basic key-bindings for navigation, you may refer to the <a href="http://www.emacswiki.org/emacs/EmacsNewbieKeyReference">Emacs Wiki page</a>.</p>

<p>Finally, once you really get the hang of Emacs, it&rsquo;s basically like dark magic. Check out some videos on the <a href="http://emacsrocks.com">Emacs rocks page</a> to see this magic in action.</p>

<p>If you&rsquo;re addicted to vi there&rsquo;s a funny song on GNU&rsquo;s website : <a href="http://www.gnu.org/fun/jokes/vi.song.html">&lsquo;Addicted to vi&rsquo;</a> :stuck_out_tongue:</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
