<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[tags:pre-upgrade | Umar Ahmad]]></title>
  <link href="http://gleek.github.io/blog/tags/pre-upgrade/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://gleek.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2017-04-08T01:35:17+05:30</updated>
  <id>http://gleek.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Umar Ahmad]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Migrating to Fedora 20]]></title>
    <link href="http://gleek.github.io/blog/2014/03/24/migrating-to-fedora-20/"/>
    <updated>2014-03-24T20:32:50+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://gleek.github.io/blog/2014/03/24/migrating-to-fedora-20</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://fedoraproject.org/get-fedora"><img src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/uqGbIS_J6m_AloaEhWeG0IZ6G4iWSYBUDMJ8kX3aRRxLHhiruma365lgbRW877VHiSbMP1ivNISekZl1aUQGw13Z6SIcZEJ2nqp_Lt-I0UuPfmiypBz7iM8m3vvWD9ijUSB8u0Fa4IbJaXgQdlGCjAP1hBVvPcfVvDgQ4--LvLl18fOLV-5vk-l4zPU4calXUlOaNDGw_dCPLM0RO42YllDiAN669vFCR1g9PIftUhKCE271lXeOZmo4hp_AICCQNppWpQS-mD7I8zYx_BAqvTPdwhPzkHYG-ZU33Jz2N3-uqEGpefU7QaklxXVpBG3-_VmOmwXUNBhOa0LHUVpcTa4JA_lz2D5AcwhwAGMyEbjaTAAOjI2zxrg9wuF6R8nitmQREcfs4R1I5DwLjuOlHLYdgWLHx_AHSd-aB4Lp6Slx29vUvVtgD6MIMQUB_sH60bvT81LM-OTlQbO35yyHXI5ETyePfzcSeblRUN96Ecu3D67xMLdujDfje3t8_7gQkC5IcUpfgYVOukd_bi6kgqMaF2c5_KXD1tpt7PhbnZ9N7hQ8W1uveUdurWZik1NcFs7hMMmJgZjf-0eSqo56vX12_k4D391EAxe1L6hSE9UHzmYFKSZj_FDtD_Q97yg5hn2CC6exVqQZSnVRqkKPXO1vvQRnZFHpvhGapvPIgg=w200-h100-no" alt="Fedora 20" style=" display:block;margin:auto;"></a></p>

<p>I&rsquo;ve been a Fedora Fan-boy ever-since I started using it three years ago and Fedora 17 is the only Linux Based Distro which lasted for more than a year on my laptop. But just as every good thing has to come to an end, my company with Fedora 17 had completed it&rsquo;s lifetime. <!-- more --></p>

<h4>Why did I stick with it ?</h4>

<p>To be honest, I was too scared to move on to a different O.S. because of the compatibility issues which my system has with Linux. To name the few:</p>

<ul>
<li>Extra media/function keys don&rsquo;t work</li></li>
<li>Battery Applet can&rsquo;t detect change in battery-charging status</li>
<li>Linux goes into kernel-panic if connected with Bluetooth Mobile Internet (<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bluetooth_profile#Dial-up_Networking_Profile_.28DUN.29">DUN</a>)</li>
<li><del>Wrong Resolution detected by X </del>(Bug Resolved after an update)</li>
<li>Wi-fi cannot connect to Ad-Hoc network</li>
<li>Wi-fi cannot create Hotspot</li>
<li>and many more minor bugs&hellip;..</li>
</ul>


<p>The problem is that every time I install a new linux distro I have to fight with some new even more puzzling bugs, and that is some tough battle to fight. So once I finally settled myself with Fedora 17, I never dared to move to some other O.S.</p>

<h3>Why did I upgrade ?</h3>

<p>Well, all things die with time and so did Fedora 17. Updates started depleting and new packages stalled. Considering these points and applaud for Fedora 20 helped me to move.</p>

<h3>How ?</h3>

<p>Once I decided to move on to Fedora 20 , I went researching about the methods and issues people had while upgrading fedora. Most of it was concerned with efi the new &lsquo;use only Windows&rsquo; policy of the hardware vendors&hellip;but that wasn&rsquo;t the case with me. So I moved on.
I found many ways to upgrade to f20:</p>

<ul>
<li>Using <a href="http://fedoraproject.org/wiki/FedUp">Fedup</a> (Recommended, but sadly not available for F17 :disappointed: )</li>
<li>Using <a href="http://fedoraproject.org/wiki/Upgrading_Fedora_using_yum">yum</a> (Highly unstable&hellip;not recommended)</li>
<li>Using <a href="https://fedoraproject.org/wiki/How_to_use_PreUpgrade">pre-upgrade</a></li>
<li>Installing with boot-media</li>
</ul>


<p>The first two options were rejected instantly because of lack of support.
<strong>Pre-Upgrade</strong>: looked nice, but <strong>even a fully-updated system didn&rsquo;t show any new releases of Fedora</strong> in the Pre-Upgrade Window.
Since I was left with no choice, I adapted the old-school method of formatting the partition and re-installing everything&hellip;
Since I was too desperate to try F20 I didn&rsquo;t think of the consequences and went on with the method.</p>

<ul>
<li>I backed up my home folder</li>
<li>Got the name of every package installed with <code>rpm  -qa --qf '%{NAME}\n'</code></li>
</ul>


<p>and when on to format the partition.</p>

<h3>The Dumb Review</h3>

<h4>What&rsquo;s awesome?</h4>

<p>The best thing about Fedora 20 is the new Gnome-Shell 3.10 with much more cleaner interface. The gnome apps are awesome, and lots of bugs have been fixed.
&ndash; The applications list is sorted out and grouped in a better manner.</li>
&ndash; I don&rsquo;t know how but all the applications which had problem running on previous versions of Fedora, such as Wine or Conky, worked fine now.</li></p>

<h4>What&rsquo;s not so awesome</h4>

<ul>
<li>My old GTK+ and Gnome-Shell themes don&rsquo;t work anymore. I had to tweak every old thing a bit.</li></li>
<li>The top-bar is a bit too compact for me. I would have loved some more options such as my current connectivity status, etc.</li></li>
<li>It&rsquo;s still a tiring task to actually edit the application list. It would be better if there could be options to add applications to the list.</li></li>
</ul>


<h4>What Sucks?</h4>

<ul>
<li><strong>That damn Nautilus :</strong>Nautilus is a big setback. They have disabled the backspace key and the search is now recursive. They have also disabled the Split-View. In short they have removed everything I loved about Nautilus.</li>
</ul>


<p>I could find only one solution to fix all the problems &ndash; Degrade to the previous version.</p>

<p><strong>Note: You can fix the backspace feature <a href="http://askubuntu.com/questions/289535/bring-back-backspace-keyboard-shortcuts-on-nautilus-and-thunar" title="">(Ask Ubuntu)</a></strong></p>

<p>I&rsquo;m sure to find some more bugs as I move Along ,and this page will be updated :stuck_out_tongue:</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
