<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Life | Umar Ahmad]]></title>
  <link href="http://gleek.github.io/blog/categories/life/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://gleek.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2017-04-17T20:54:59+05:30</updated>
  <id>http://gleek.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Umar Ahmad]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[GSOC Midterms: Half Over is Half Left]]></title>
    <link href="http://gleek.github.io/blog/2014/06/29/gsoc-midterms-half-over-is-half-left/"/>
    <updated>2014-06-29T16:30:07+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://gleek.github.io/blog/2014/06/29/gsoc-midterms-half-over-is-half-left</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div align="center">
<img src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/O2hQSeV_aZFFQH0PQgh-AV5c9b3Gvzx8U3_O2OLidJXUOCnWGPLN6DyE7KdOXXWG1KZuSGer-0sDzHXoHjv2bGtPnXtE4jVoygB7IhFoharxvP-GGul4UAe68sL7Jp8O0y7PG9VneRwmhFOuIFFeXAVy4fpBbJ-DDV4ymv-VwnQFh31BEMokAHwDb2E2jB3R4PHWKN-GptRNHWG8SGbndLXREoi-lyRUo9DSMEAeiUyrCwhc4-UFU4hvE8JksEs8tXSL-rQ6dgO9Qjw7u1jYidXRX8kRKaj1t0RV0R4PjvJhkn6-u_1ODqWfIMGfx_MQ_uCS1FQv503oAC1BArzbRwEjLX0sp7RhKf0-EeWuna3UDLlbanOJd5alAFbj0Z2HKRmD58rStwQIvLheLpjCGmKdeXEo3xB5fHHtx8zJLksjU2cCxFgAC71tXiUeeLZ2WYWups5Q7U72B1mXzGqXUQFH1E-GtfXaD1tZuHJ5I-n13A-lKvPCEK5hWYF8ImRAa3Kg2vv3tVnvUIPWcMcuoQO1RJDZik5YImF8F7SU_FCHavtaEJz5AGaQYn3r8DVYHM2WePN_htsPV7Gt-KNPfd9wMbVHY5keT_iTRQ0rYPhhKPojx2Rq7mkGPtq_SVdOScX5quCjjRzaFzx836GLqeyhim7cn9RB9KHvQu_b8g=w600-h160-no"/>
</div>


<br>


<p>GSOC Midterms ended few days back and it&rsquo;s been fun so far. In my previous post I briefly touched upon my project, <strong><a href="https://www.github.com/gleek/fluxpocket">fluxpocket</a></strong> , which is an extended service for <strong><a href="http://www.drupal.org/project/fluxservice">fluxservices</a></strong>, which is based upon <strong><a href="http://www.fluxkraft.com">fluxkraft</a></strong>, which runs on <strong><a href="http://www.drupal.org/project/rules">rules</a></strong>, which is based on <strong><a href="http://www.drupal.org">Drupal</a></strong>!!</p>

<!-- more -->


<div align="center">
<img src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/ogTFYEpIzoDLq1yNZWVxpd0WCcoAclC8x5bCqGrO1n7B8TPirtTKVwQ3Xc0ccvLa8bOT7WRV7aFlT-ut1ldluZQw7Zdc-I8SMFSemoMZGAbHUheeLxQPQElr5hz0DtPpqMqNcE22ZFT4REP9BGHHbXospKBsZGo6F-h8D_t6zOMpHWsa_jt-A74huWTOied0-YLTK-F20Byl-pBdjefga60uDP3BiN0SVBEPkovWigv8-GLAiGw6v_zxtmqUXq3bYc8pKxiAqTu8r0RCKBO5OfUE8yqLfFpb9Qm_dX5y6pyIofEw__du1ORg2D7HxBjfNFU-6VXJkE_JGSt-SHF9s0vAK15_nLJIDFAM92aLTjupzmhgp8z-tcPMNPjRyY3KeYyfdUsMEnXFNd2KXGnejvJn80B3E3_3mOgMHYa-zfcdNo7tVg38935IgFwrZDjZ6HqD98_f-ra2wpr8LzxRH7lF0ObWWM-67aGKkdK7JC2zmndQqu265gLyY8CgqWorGr1SdN9KeFANnJ84ZQoZt_SeMpxcAjojFgsnbS7O2hhKbAIiIWI7ITeospKVJu-0E-GLNZee9eIEkiY0W6E-e0fWC-pX-E5AA2TuBITAC99YiGhvRUII2xEPq4JzBPG_6jkCZuM3IUAF31SQ3R-UsYv4myJLoeQK1Z3ygG9UWA=s300" width="300"/>
</div>


<br>


<p>Well, it gets a bit confusing sometimes. But for making things easier, <a href="https://ifttt.com/recipes?channel=pocket#popular">consider these ifttt services</a>, (take a minute for that), now imagine these running on your own server or website and all the keys to your valuable data secured &ndash; and most importantly &ndash; under your control!</p>

<h3>What Works so far</h3>

<p><strong>The Actions</strong>. You can perform almost all the actions supported by Pocket through the API. Thus some examples of what you can do so far are:</p>

<ul>
<li>Posting your Posts simultaneously to Drupal and Pocket</li>
<li>Getting your new Feeds directly in Pocket</li>
<li>Posting links to favorite tweets to Pocket
&hellip;.list goes on, but you get the idea :wink:</li>
</ul>


<h3>What&rsquo;s left</h3>

<p><strong>The Events</strong>. The events or triggers are currently under-development and will be under my focus for most of the left-over period. The Events are the portion which react to the changes in the pocket, such as addition of new URL. It will be done by polling the pocket server for any changes in the pocket list after specified interval.</p>

<p><strong>Documentation</strong>. The fluxservices are not yet properly documented. This will be my priority after I finish up with the Events.</p>

<h3>How&rsquo;s everything else?</h3>

<p>I have done some changes on how I manage things regarding the project , for instance, I now use <a href="https://github.com/Gleek/fluxpocket/issues">github milestones and issues</a> to track my progress instead of completely depending on titanpad for that.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;ve also stopped pushing my code to my <a href="https://www.drupal.org/node/2282655">drupal sandbox</a> and I only update my <a href="https://www.github.com/fluxpocket">github repository</a> now. I&rsquo;ll transfer it to drupal when the project&rsquo;s complete.</p>

<p>Other than that I&rsquo;ve started to track my time using <a href="https://github.com/projecthamster/hamster">hamster</a> which tells me that I spend more time researching than actual coding. It also tells me that T.V. is a real time killer :grimacing:.
(P.S. I don&rsquo;t track the sleeping hours&hellip;the long ones)</p>

<p><img src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/HOlEm2-_EvezvAO4CEUKdBGT8bh5O2ZMcY4ukToz_mt5XDYn2jLQIRqMLQKOnAzzEGPUpxbrPpT2PpcO2iQzwLIneSzggaxw41d2q6io84TzE53Hhc8m-4fqW1bFzH2FB3cWqpkx2eZZp9NC80kDw1Yy37zv4--fzCc9TTD8xCcOb2iVLWJtovj_uRcbYcjKUPFdBw8c3e-iiLjQ-henqDk2HXDRbOlwlo22w0XAwqfW2S5s1zrT4GIgFxjEZmXoguQxV5dYw7sTb3hBAgdJ9KVhduYi3LvMaOuLHnBwzfwYfRKFCmv_k6DzevvLA9goDE0WDEdWpXbrSzSbJXhQaHNgpyomiPEpDgrOqu0yadVF-NuKbn-raEtT0DWaes53CxiDUKIHyPa_hqfddsNq8kNSG0bzC2Wr1HqU1d-81sjwjYm4-go1cN2vWh_rOlKmeTNP1PjRlMxsX1UccRk5qH0Wkn7A7i--O46wlH0yyOocjXDo1ooQUTLLbNShM6xMymrB_vA-o4EBUXEZRKhw0YLgz19lZXQ8pGldbcwVPBZvTf9W_IXP2Oo7NThCUeT-qRM-2MZD9tslPZF2pf-A9ctdQkJVc1gvhHiUHaY2e567_ryW-O1L=w1286-h422-no" alt="time overview" /></p>

<p>Other than that I might have misconfigured my mind&rsquo;s clock cycle. I am usually sleeping when the &lsquo;normal&rsquo; humans work and work when they sleep.. and it&rsquo;s really hard to get rid of this schedule.</p>

<p>I wish to write more but <a href="https://github.com/projecthamster/hamster">hamster</a> tells  me that I&rsquo;ve spend far more time on this than originally anticipated. So I&rsquo;m gonna switch back to coding and hope everything works out in the end.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[GSOC - Here We Go]]></title>
    <link href="http://gleek.github.io/blog/2014/06/12/gsoc-here-we-go/"/>
    <updated>2014-06-12T05:45:04+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://gleek.github.io/blog/2014/06/12/gsoc-here-we-go</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/-_eXnV87hecb2o5FZfatpmppOXSBupYVE2Xr8WIdxbi4tJqYW-iH-Y-ptJ2zDItA3N8XYuT71fmdxkP5RBWMJIxh2wGEPnOyaohoLbxxaT8cSNc67QQH2581_7ov2-rTPC5t9ro1UxN92jY8eNCF1mw-m879yjWX_H9vhZJVdVnrQRCEw5GHLL_k_Any-hYsIhOl06Paafst7kd4e-1rTORw6-TReVjZZQs6uYZSS2HTqB0g-_h2Zkp9g3UXcrrKcNucr-CYtilEIK_PRi_lUeRdNtU1rsGWrakkMDUXMuKy-ReIlBxUgc5Mj8iDde1RGqFf663lKQ5JhZb6nIiQuTnnqzg1MoynXFkqJsDaztSanuEm7uSWhwQ_gVDQjcGK7eVykXCa4JBZnucDlZBYVurJDk7wfUASCp5LvPXD3Ord3kAyLVZupq9bdjC28zGyGc8H6QC-LrUTxOkgyAoxjaifSlxTbcFao5snSSYPf-Whxj73Vzt2c2p0uHR_ySuBfRlSJL6Ul8cnp3KYEkiMQbAwYuAVlTSka-0Ch3uppYGS57dztOpyVawV-v2W4ipXj3fpmRYSC7jJA29ztsrCYZQKahhBaQREqrtJRgG5_zqCryLyn7vrzgoVXYOeX5MUW_P--Np4KEChrnTGp1C0Of2H4Jn26Ja4_Its7XEC_A=w924-h156-no" alt="GSOC 2014" /></p>

<br>


<h4>What?</h4>

<p>Google Summer of Code is happening this year with over <a href="http://www.google-melange.com/gsoc/org/list/public/google/gsoc2014">190 participating organizations</a> and with a total of <a href="http://google-opensource.blogspot.in/2014/05/google-summer-of-code-2014-by-numbers.html">1307 students</a> selected all round the globe, and being one of them is truly awesome :sunglasses:. <!-- more --></p>

<h4>How?</h4>

<p>Initially my expectations of being accepted were very low, but I also had nothing to lose. With this thought and a little persuasion from one of my friends I decided to <em>at least check the organizations and there proposals</em>. Being a Web maniac I quickly searched for organizations based on Web Technologies and found Drupal to be one of the organizations I was already familiar.</p>

<h4>Getting with Drupal and fluxpocket</h4>

<p>I quickly glanced through the <a href="https://groups.drupal.org/node/407793">projects list</a> with a lot of cool projects, but one of them caught my attention. It was the integration of the Pocket API with <a href="http://www.fluxkraft.com">fluxkraft</a>. I prepared a proposal, discussed the prospects of the project with the mentors and the next thing I know is that my name popped in the list of 13 <a href="http://www.google-melange.com/gsoc/projects/list/google/gsoc2014">accepted students</a> from drupal. :relaxed:</p>

<h4>What am I doing?</h4>

<p>Fluxkraft is a module suite and distribution for automating your social media work flows! It is an OpenSource alternative to services like <a href="http://ifttt.com">IfTtT</a>, <a href="https://zapier.com/">Zapier</a> or <a href="https://cloudwork.com/">Cloudwork</a>. For really becoming a usable alternative more and more services should be integrated to Fluxkraft.</p>

<p>The <a href="http://getpocket.com">Pocket</a>(formerly Read It Later) application allows the user to save an article or web page to read later. The article is then sent to the user&rsquo;s Pocket list (synced to all of their devices) for offline reading. Pocket removes clutter from articles and allows the user to adjust text settings for easier reading. With over 9 million Pocket users and more than 240 million saves, Pocket automation as a fluxkraft service has a very high potential.</p>

<p>As a result of the Project there should be a Drupal Module that adds Pocket functionality to fluxkraft. For example making it possible to retrieve and post articles to Pocket, filtering stored items by tag and adding and removing tags to items, Modifying the existing state of items etc. The goal is also to update the documentation to support other developers for implementing new services like Youtube, Github, Yammer etc.</p>

<h4>Links</h4>

<ul>
<li>You might find my <strong><a href="http://goo.gl/g5UpZY">proposal</a></strong> a bit more helpful as far as technical details are concerned.</li>
<li><a href="https://drupal.org/u/umar-ahmad">My drupal user account</a></li>
<li>You can find the <strong>code in my <a href="https://github.com/Gleek/fluxpocket">github repository</a> and as a <a href="https://drupal.org/node/2282655">sandbox project on drupal</a></strong></li>
</ul>


<p>I&rsquo;ll be posting my experiences, journey, success and failures <a href="/blog/tags/gsoc">here</a> on my blog. Hoping to have an exciting summer.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[GSF Hacks]]></title>
    <link href="http://gleek.github.io/blog/2014/05/08/gsf-hacks/"/>
    <updated>2014-05-08T03:01:30+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://gleek.github.io/blog/2014/05/08/gsf-hacks</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/7zBCup0aXx-KUJveJNOxISqBj3JXPaPY9u05q9Akw3EqIICRgExww1BMImw25FkodIVfACX6cC7OepuQz4kpvkniONdYjrb9fwTqRI06e3OwMtQyzew9zviROsNkWi49fC_5C0wb3AVEGg55HvpBLTkVdMT1nsu2HwaleXumrALCPmbaNjsO_dcnNoVwmNmVALbXuMUDM87MSpz9Lt746gU1HiV8XnFxroGCv_AdQ3rA3h7eNWjQIyS-wqFiuamL7EF6jdXo0LUVGDJWSuzShCwHGXKwwZ4ixY3RVerIG8jJ7zupxT94DshLMzMU_jYQk6pLm7qLFnCntEB8hakWZWLShUpKrBl_4gJ4RlW9dH3fVsqbnzOKW3HnVZpIAErQOctUDtbmqgW-_WGrmBbFI8Jk5cfBjCC9SXs9wAqZt2R-BwvYXR__ahl9rDiJRdPXB1GQQNpnRgB_dCyMTBrW-KnqWoI_KN4kwSHI1ARYDNC3v1OM-tc_3nPIsjy_JwoxZ4sG4cTsHbefXt6BL2HnETD77GmYCx9TWZb-j_wnnY0xHRBNU8kOHOZCFJ8_B0Z3S4rhTKBCV9U9s6B5UgChO_DhtlOdv1dgisSgPYXahpo1chmtSNluBBIfdSQ5odHBNJVITuLRDqUod8Dm-LzmJdcBQmpgse-VUDvCFe7qMA=s370" style=" display:block;margin:auto;" width="370"/></p>

<p>Last month some of my friends and I went to a hackathon organized by <a href="http://www.gsfindia.com/hacks/">GSF India</a>. This hackathon was particularly interesting since almost all the participants were amongst the top ranked from <a href="http://www.hackerearth.com/">Hacker Earth</a> and thus a tough competition was expected.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>The participating teams had to choose one challenge to compete. Our team chose shine.com challenge which involved improving their registration system in an innovative manner.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.shine.com">Shine.com</a> is a website for job finding. We could easily see problems with the registration system, which could be solved. What we built was a utility which involved an IVR, Voice Recognition system, Resume Parsing (PDF/DOC) and an Android App for smart phones as well as not so smart phones.</p>

<ul>
<li><p><a href="http://www.kookoo.in/">Kookoo</a> API and AT&amp;T voice parsing API was used in the <strong>IVR system</strong>. The Kookoo system recorded the voice of a person <em>by a simple phone call</em> and AT&amp;T API helped us parse it. Thus making it suitable for any mobile phone.</p></li>
<li><p>We also made a <strong>CV/Resume Parser</strong> with a help of small <code>cURL</code> hack on rchilli CV Parser. It allowed the user to upload his resume and getting his details automagically filled in the form.</p></li>
<li><p>On the top of everything we also made an <strong>Android App</strong> which again does all the above things.</p></li>
</ul>


<p><strong>You can find the code on <a href="https://github.com/Gleek/gsfhack">Github</a></strong></p>

<p>The good thing is that our hard work paid off and we won the challenge.
What&rsquo;s better than a 2 days of coding with free food , infinite Red-Bulls, a cool tablet and a little cash. Well other than that we also got a cool sipper and a t-shirt.</p>

<p>Here&rsquo;s a photo of our team with two of the judges</p>

<p><img src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/e6tC7XObOye9I067tEV_k0Hhl5KggZ7V62u1KsWAak6YRSDH3q61c4bVaOen_NaNpD0T_PyEeSiVe-lrrGTivNrTq5EaYKQRZ-gD_oJygYQXiK2LGmkv3wH8lKWxVlB0FGoAy57PCK19m1fIF-C3Vho9fLoIT_MyQFTVihhV_FT6bEL16WwfY_un99vuJSdPRu_ipOf0sijwZJ2g12-bDLJgvfbXw9VHRw9lWe72DSHEh4sE5x5aIOzR_OraKF2isC6lBSTKHvnAdzQu0O2d-sm92w3CJT8QQpklEb-P9bZuUi075lNzhtRdmusL503TlRPY7bvJYHsrlQTTIaLQ2VnTUcdaejI13vxul8XKbxOynVewB9c5rVV61bt9JAG7yx-VKK7IUqGZ2gMhhbvE4E76rX9rvjr0qGjdYG7-2Nk8FMSJGcfdUxiHr790W2TOn5aIXwEnqMyeQHd0V5jCkvSOgivTQSinXZuBst5Lpung2ax-joCVCmWWfUigLaBSNa8roRum6xdhSfUzOqbVle5CgPlThVMc6JkT1qSsQ2cMBRVyKmTyZMluYs0RBIUoztM_YzVHQqvbtLgXIxdKkm6WNZjS6upMng6JO2m0BWmbOhWKezsDalnBLuVJiGuGANGrbz-pvOFKtefjbl9J-82blWUPAd1cj4pQA87xcw=w1016-h366-no" alt="Team Octane" /></p>

<p>You can find the photos on <a href="https://www.facebook.com/GSFINDIAACCELERATOR/albums/719167938135941/">Facebook</a> and some media coverage at <a href="http://yourstory.com/2014/04/gsfhacks/">YourStory</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[From WordPress to Octopress]]></title>
    <link href="http://gleek.github.io/blog/2014/04/18/from-wordpress-to-octopress/"/>
    <updated>2014-04-18T20:07:03+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://gleek.github.io/blog/2014/04/18/from-wordpress-to-octopress</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em>This post is about choosing Octopress over <strong>WordPress hosted</strong> blog, it does not talk about WordPress as a framework.</em></p>

<p>It has been a very few days I started this blog. Now I feel a bit of a weird pride in announcing that this may be the last post on the wordpress, it&rsquo;s now hosted on github &ndash; <a href="http://gleek.github.io/">http://gleek.github.io</a> , and powered by Octopress.</p>

<!-- more -->


<h3>Why I chose WordPress?</h3>

<p>When I first thought about blogging, the first thing that came to my mind was choosing the right framework for it. Three of them came to my mind, namely Drupal, Wordpress and Octopress. Since I didn&rsquo;t have any reliable hosting at that time and had previous experience with WordPress, I decided to go with blog hosted on Wordpress.com.</p>

<h3>The problems</h3>

<p>What I didn&rsquo;t realize at that time was that <strong>installing and using wordpress, on an owned server, was a lot different that hosting a blog on Wordpress.com.</strong></p>

<p>The main problem is that <strong>I have no desire to empty my pockets on a blog, but still demand full control over it.</strong></p>

<p>WordPress sets up a free blog with a theme, but I had to pay even for the slightest tweak. So most of my problems which weren&rsquo;t expected initially were:</p>

<ul>
<li>There are a lot of themes which were usable for free, but tweaking the themes is not tolerated without costing you some bucks.</li>
<li>I couldn&rsquo;t control the back-end of the blog. (I expected that, actually :grin: )</li>
<li>You can&rsquo;t write JavaScript</li>
<li>You can&rsquo;t write your CSS without paying a little something. I had to write some inline CSS to make something a little prettier.</li>
<li>WordPress puts its advertisements at the end of every blog post.</li>
<li>Custom WordPress plugins cannot be used in the blog.</li>
</ul>


<h3>Switching to Octopress</h3>

<p>Disappointed by WordPress, hosting my blog on Github or Heroku with Octopress seemed to be the only option. Since I keep almost all my projects on github, I chose the same for the blog. There were some initial problems while setting up the blog. But <a href="https://github.com/imathis/octopress/issues">issue queue</a> helped me in solving them.</p>

<p> <strong>Pros</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>I get the content control over my website. Above mentioned problems in wordpress site such as no JS/CSS support is now solved.</li>
<li>It&rsquo;s not necessary to be online while you write the blog</li>
<li>Git is used to manage the blog which makes it easy to manage.</li>
<li>Static pages makes it incredibly fast.</li>
<li>Posts are written in Markdown</li>
</ul>


<p><strong>Cons</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>Initial installation and setup is a bit time-taking.</li>
<li>Your blog is restricted to your local machine. To use a different machine to blog, you&rsquo;ll have to clone entire blog on it.(Which also eliminates using mobiles for blogging)</li>
<li>For large websites generating the pages can take some time, though using <code>rake isolate[path/to/post.markdown]</code> and <code>rake integrate</code> may solve the problem if you are working on a single post. Find more on <a href="http://blog.pixelingene.com/2011/09/tips-for-speeding-up-octopress-site-generation/">Pavan&rsquo;s blog</a></li>
</ul>


<p>You can take a look at performance aspect of Octopress on <a href="http://decodize.com/html/moving-from-wordpress-to-octopress/">Praveen&rsquo;s Blog</a>.</p>

<h3>Summary</h3>

<p>Choosing a framework for a Blog is a matter of choice. As far as I am concerned I&rsquo;m satisfied with the results Octopress is giving me. I might remind you that this post was on my experience in blogging at <a href="http://noobpanic.wordpress.com">WordPress</a> and on <a href="http://gleek.github.io">Octopress</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Migrating to Fedora 20]]></title>
    <link href="http://gleek.github.io/blog/2014/03/24/migrating-to-fedora-20/"/>
    <updated>2014-03-24T20:32:50+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://gleek.github.io/blog/2014/03/24/migrating-to-fedora-20</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://fedoraproject.org/get-fedora"><img src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/uqGbIS_J6m_AloaEhWeG0IZ6G4iWSYBUDMJ8kX3aRRxLHhiruma365lgbRW877VHiSbMP1ivNISekZl1aUQGw13Z6SIcZEJ2nqp_Lt-I0UuPfmiypBz7iM8m3vvWD9ijUSB8u0Fa4IbJaXgQdlGCjAP1hBVvPcfVvDgQ4--LvLl18fOLV-5vk-l4zPU4calXUlOaNDGw_dCPLM0RO42YllDiAN669vFCR1g9PIftUhKCE271lXeOZmo4hp_AICCQNppWpQS-mD7I8zYx_BAqvTPdwhPzkHYG-ZU33Jz2N3-uqEGpefU7QaklxXVpBG3-_VmOmwXUNBhOa0LHUVpcTa4JA_lz2D5AcwhwAGMyEbjaTAAOjI2zxrg9wuF6R8nitmQREcfs4R1I5DwLjuOlHLYdgWLHx_AHSd-aB4Lp6Slx29vUvVtgD6MIMQUB_sH60bvT81LM-OTlQbO35yyHXI5ETyePfzcSeblRUN96Ecu3D67xMLdujDfje3t8_7gQkC5IcUpfgYVOukd_bi6kgqMaF2c5_KXD1tpt7PhbnZ9N7hQ8W1uveUdurWZik1NcFs7hMMmJgZjf-0eSqo56vX12_k4D391EAxe1L6hSE9UHzmYFKSZj_FDtD_Q97yg5hn2CC6exVqQZSnVRqkKPXO1vvQRnZFHpvhGapvPIgg=w200-h100-no" alt="Fedora 20" style=" display:block;margin:auto;"></a></p>

<p>I&rsquo;ve been a Fedora Fan-boy ever-since I started using it three years ago and Fedora 17 is the only Linux Based Distro which lasted for more than a year on my laptop. But just as every good thing has to come to an end, my company with Fedora 17 had completed it&rsquo;s lifetime. <!-- more --></p>

<h4>Why did I stick with it ?</h4>

<p>To be honest, I was too scared to move on to a different O.S. because of the compatibility issues which my system has with Linux. To name the few:</p>

<ul>
<li>Extra media/function keys don&rsquo;t work</li></li>
<li>Battery Applet can&rsquo;t detect change in battery-charging status</li>
<li>Linux goes into kernel-panic if connected with Bluetooth Mobile Internet (<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bluetooth_profile#Dial-up_Networking_Profile_.28DUN.29">DUN</a>)</li>
<li><del>Wrong Resolution detected by X </del>(Bug Resolved after an update)</li>
<li>Wi-fi cannot connect to Ad-Hoc network</li>
<li>Wi-fi cannot create Hotspot</li>
<li>and many more minor bugs&hellip;..</li>
</ul>


<p>The problem is that every time I install a new linux distro I have to fight with some new even more puzzling bugs, and that is some tough battle to fight. So once I finally settled myself with Fedora 17, I never dared to move to some other O.S.</p>

<h3>Why did I upgrade ?</h3>

<p>Well, all things die with time and so did Fedora 17. Updates started depleting and new packages stalled. Considering these points and applaud for Fedora 20 helped me to move.</p>

<h3>How ?</h3>

<p>Once I decided to move on to Fedora 20 , I went researching about the methods and issues people had while upgrading fedora. Most of it was concerned with efi the new &lsquo;use only Windows&rsquo; policy of the hardware vendors&hellip;but that wasn&rsquo;t the case with me. So I moved on.
I found many ways to upgrade to f20:</p>

<ul>
<li>Using <a href="http://fedoraproject.org/wiki/FedUp">Fedup</a> (Recommended, but sadly not available for F17 :disappointed: )</li>
<li>Using <a href="http://fedoraproject.org/wiki/Upgrading_Fedora_using_yum">yum</a> (Highly unstable&hellip;not recommended)</li>
<li>Using <a href="https://fedoraproject.org/wiki/How_to_use_PreUpgrade">pre-upgrade</a></li>
<li>Installing with boot-media</li>
</ul>


<p>The first two options were rejected instantly because of lack of support.
<strong>Pre-Upgrade</strong>: looked nice, but <strong>even a fully-updated system didn&rsquo;t show any new releases of Fedora</strong> in the Pre-Upgrade Window.
Since I was left with no choice, I adapted the old-school method of formatting the partition and re-installing everything&hellip;
Since I was too desperate to try F20 I didn&rsquo;t think of the consequences and went on with the method.</p>

<ul>
<li>I backed up my home folder</li>
<li>Got the name of every package installed with <code>rpm  -qa --qf '%{NAME}\n'</code></li>
</ul>


<p>and when on to format the partition.</p>

<h3>The Dumb Review</h3>

<h4>What&rsquo;s awesome?</h4>

<p>The best thing about Fedora 20 is the new Gnome-Shell 3.10 with much more cleaner interface. The gnome apps are awesome, and lots of bugs have been fixed.
&ndash; The applications list is sorted out and grouped in a better manner.</li>
&ndash; I don&rsquo;t know how but all the applications which had problem running on previous versions of Fedora, such as Wine or Conky, worked fine now.</li></p>

<h4>What&rsquo;s not so awesome</h4>

<ul>
<li>My old GTK+ and Gnome-Shell themes don&rsquo;t work anymore. I had to tweak every old thing a bit.</li></li>
<li>The top-bar is a bit too compact for me. I would have loved some more options such as my current connectivity status, etc.</li></li>
<li>It&rsquo;s still a tiring task to actually edit the application list. It would be better if there could be options to add applications to the list.</li></li>
</ul>


<h4>What Sucks?</h4>

<ul>
<li><strong>That damn Nautilus :</strong>Nautilus is a big setback. They have disabled the backspace key and the search is now recursive. They have also disabled the Split-View. In short they have removed everything I loved about Nautilus.</li>
</ul>


<p>I could find only one solution to fix all the problems &ndash; Degrade to the previous version.</p>

<p><strong>Note: You can fix the backspace feature <a href="http://askubuntu.com/questions/289535/bring-back-backspace-keyboard-shortcuts-on-nautilus-and-thunar" title="">(Ask Ubuntu)</a></strong></p>

<p>I&rsquo;m sure to find some more bugs as I move Along ,and this page will be updated :stuck_out_tongue:</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
