<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[tags:fn | Umar Ahmad]]></title>
  <link href="http://gleek.github.io/blog/tags/fn/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://gleek.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2017-04-29T22:45:16+05:30</updated>
  <id>http://gleek.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Umar Ahmad]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fixing Brightness Problems in Linux]]></title>
    <link href="http://gleek.github.io/blog/2014/03/04/fixing-brightness/"/>
    <updated>2014-03-04T23:51:09+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://gleek.github.io/blog/2014/03/04/fixing-brightness</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em>You can find the said applications/scripts in my <a href="https://github.com/Gleek/linux-brightness-hack">github repository</a></em>
 <img style=" display:block;margin:auto;" src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/FtDEhFz8XUmpm-kK2gXko-Y6y9SojmlX8TQPmFht1Xx15GY__hKAANFn9kcI-6wuC1sXVfRpIBE3oo-20kHJqkk0DKtQoliaT9_ruWfQVdYOEE3COC0Sc1uHL5q0X8UoCMTZuYUfNeFT1Yoe6wJVK8OOY3QlLGfvUSaUlK32PUnIb-5isnpWbwi2ZfedUYUaFmLJU1MNR3MgslxbJ4Q0TSX2BcSRWu2l_ilCf2CB3zPmXNPkOlPXLPhADIJUVlZsqtNhv7q4s8t9uvTZuMU0NpsXOooN7s7VyvpJ3YOQEYimyMB1Pz7YMNSo3nV5lCXPBn63XkIkigQ9HoYZn5oKW5CLTu3wSqMh2zYoEfvbZIrB0KEA6EMTjiirc4BnKvcs0IOTYahm5r2Ws2x7N2Pr6KnSlOWB1rHVA7dw9cRCKV2qA_tJsjKJSvlPUngWn2STRtuprHvigclTX-hMn7V24P6QTHbPilB3uQRN91iYOrNo7pkLhgo-WmGo6sABukUM4ETwUVSUUgTSsxYrD9aBoZz7WOOZo0Z4awGcDQgNXCzg5Rza81TVmRxa7cwbIEMu21TZUaaEN9Kot3f6q1iaYnos_zFTMhrau4lQVzZRNbrVxx5pY8IjT8i3dix8zPDv-RZgcpm7ExPrxr8_zcSXJbdgay-9cN7AP7yFZxbR9w=s240-no" height="240" width="240" alt="Brightness Gnome" /></p>

<p>This is a problem which I faced since the beginning I installed Linux. My system neither recognized my display settings nor those damn shortcut keys (the combination of <kbd>fn</kbd> keys) worked , so I ended up getting a dark screen (with zero brightness) every time the system starts-up. I couldn&rsquo;t even change the brightness with those faulty shortcut keys!!</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>So the obvious question was:</p>

<h4>How the hell did I work with no display?</h4>

<p>I worked in recovery mode!! To be honest I started to hate my Fedora &lsquo;cause of that bulgy screen I would get in 800×600 resolution mode. Since I was a noobier noob at that time I decided to work with that. Later I found a silly workaround by &ldquo;practicing&rdquo; changing brightness in recovery mode and then &ldquo;actually&rdquo; changing brightness without the display on normal mode to get the display :astonished: &hellip;Yeah..Lame!</p>

<h2>The actual workaround..</h2>

<p>I had to find a way to change the brightness of the display by a script of some sort, which can be automated later by a keyboard shortcut or at system start-up.</p>

<h3>Method I : Editing the brightness file</h3>

<p>I found out that the actual brightness file was</p>

<p><code>/sys/class/backlight/acpi_video0/brightness</code></p>

<p>or</p>

<p><code>/sys/class/backlight/intel_backlight/brightness</code></p>

<p>and changing them with root access changes the brightness.
The problem here was that I wasn&rsquo;t able to give a script root access without it prompting for a password. I moved the other way since I couldn&rsquo;t figure that out.</p>

<p>Recently, I figured out the way to give the scripts root access by editing <code>/etc/sudoers/</code> file and adding</p>

<p><code>bash
$user ALL=(ALL) NOPASSWD: $path_to_script
</code></p>

<p>where <code>$user</code> is the user-name and <code>$path_to_script</code> is what it says it is!</p>

<h3>Method II: Making a Python Script</h3>

<p>After some researching I found out about the <a href="http://www.freedesktop.org/wiki/Software/dbus/">dbus module of python</a>, which basically could help me <code>get</code> or <code>set</code> the brightness. Using this and a little argument parsing I was successfully able to make a script which changed the brightness.
<strong>Update:</strong> <em>This method doesn&rsquo;t work on Gnome-Shell v3.10 :worried: . I will update a patch soon.</em></p>

<h3>Method III :Emulating brightness keys with xdotool</h3>

<p>The <a href="http://www.semicomplete.com/projects/xdotool/">Xdotool</a> can be used to emulate the brightness virtual key <code>xdotool key XF86MonBrightnessUp</code> to increase the brightness and <code>xdotool key XF86MonBrightnessDown</code> to decrease the brightness.</p>

<h3>Method IV :Using xbacklight</h3>

<p><a href="http://linux.die.net/man/1/xbacklight">xbacklight</a> is a tool adjust backlight brightness using RandR extension. It&rsquo;s the easiest way to change the brightness, without getting into details. It can be installed from the repository by a simple <code>yum</code> or <code>apt-get</code> command. Brightness can be changed using <code>xbacklight inc 10</code> to increase brightness by 10% and <code>xbacklight dec 10</code> to decrease the brightness by the same amount.</p>

<h3>Method V :When everything else fails&hellip;(using xrandr)</h3>

<p>Recently one of my friends brought his laptop to me with a problem with similar nature, yet was very different. His brightness keys were fully functional but due to some bug his brightness didn&rsquo;t change on changing the brightness through the default applet or the keys. On googling about it a bit, I found that it was a known <a href="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=753012">bug</a> with a shell script solution in one of the <a href="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=753012#c10">comments</a> using <code>xrandr</code>. I modified the shell script to make it work with keyboard shortcuts and it solved his problem 8) .</p>

<h2>Finally&hellip;Adding keyboard shortcut</h2>

<p>Once you&rsquo;ve got your script ready and working you need to automate it using a keyboard shortcut.
This can easily be done by Settings&gt;Keyboard&gt;Shortcuts&gt;Custom Shortcuts
and add your application
(Warning:Your keyboard shortcut shouldn&rsquo;t overlap with already mapped shortcuts. Example: You can set options such as <kbd>Ctrl</kbd> + <kbd>F3</kbd> to increase and <kbd>Ctrl</kbd>+<kbd>F2</kbd> to decrease brightness)
<strong>Tip:</strong>You can use <code>gconf-editor</code> for advanced options.</p>

<h3>Adding Scripts at start-up</h3>

<p>If you&rsquo;re having problems with your default brightness setting i.e. your brightness is either too low or too high or maybe you don&rsquo;t require a keyboard shortcut, just a way to change script automatically at start-up. You can add applications at start-up without worrying to add keyboard shortcuts like in the previous method.</p>

<p>There are many ways you can add application at start-up they are given <a href="http://askubuntu.com/questions/48321/how-do-i-start-applications-automatically-on-login">here</a> and <a href="http://stackoverflow.com/questions/7221757/run-automatically-program-on-startup-under-linux-ubuntu">here</a> but what I find simplest is using <code>gnome-session-properties</code> and simply adding the application.
Once you&rsquo;ve made those changes, you&rsquo;re ready to feel the magic of automatic brightness.</p>

<p><img src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/FCv0ym7w-1XAVZasBSuIjfElzXyEn-SG1N9WwSY7ai_OV2zeRHKS0-g00vmgLwlf1XyLlQHilYRjXbGIXxxsod4gmAfCIxdCDAj_xH7rUjCErdkJWlTbmoMBwO0ldFFZiMjgbbz4wFxk-DVU73iO3sKvjp6ykgGFHMaPaJhYlzZ9COxGmYYPRG1qGzw12NbYHj3fnoU1HNEDDPDqpUODtLofFzMNcMHj8plG9vtcUfK_Aw-RzZ_bmE-x1-c7F_EUtUYa5AOGiOW3h3moyjE53CQBd2vb1lxrByEVsfx-c8RJ-JYKjfbLcvAOu-ZWdgavz6Sg6WQduWRV-0ls6XErcPDQsXaVFiQ2rBgQeOoFu-YnbsIzK7Pm5pQ6d9EwN5ZCfswhpQyNJ1lP1wxof5bhZQJWLGPZQSIKGg5ItL72GaDpH0hPjmTmQHe8eHF0k9KCe84PKoB61cFXt9R1G8Y8ToRg2uDWadbMgMKw7Zpm2Jk6y2-687qeMexmGzexIpVge5-sJhOC7aQu6pt7AbqEvustP7x3cmNVq0s230U7z3PkfsDS_SWzJ6kNFVX6FZDOioNKcc8FGg3xcnhID16FkrpNOqM6wEmuDfnwx9FVWvx56FZU2pFYv8L2VVEBjcdszDk4FwYcGavpUE3iHk8jZPj_CUID_JDcC4ChGSOcgQ=s256-no" height="256" width="256" title="Master Joda" alt="Joda" /></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
